ecobee.com 2012-12-07

# privacy « ecobee

ecobee inc. is committed to protecting your privacy. That is why we have adopted this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy is intended to describe how your personal information is processed and used, and we will make every effort to ensure that our activities keep within the spirit of this Privacy Policy. Please note that by visiting and using ecobee.com, or any other website owned and operated by ecobee inc., you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

### What Information is ecobee inc. gathering about its visitors and how is it being used?

Every computer connected to the Internet is provided with a domain name (e.g. someispname.net) and an IP Address (e.g. 192.164.13.145). When a visitor requests a page from the ecobee website, our Web Servers automatically identify and log the HTTP request that is made to our Web Server. By itself, this information reveals nothing personal about you. In fact, the only information that we automatically gather and log is as follows:

  * The IP Address of the Site that may have Referred you

  * Your IP Address

  * The Web Page that you may have linked to us from, if any

  * The Product Identifier for Version and Make of Browser (e.g. Internet Explorer®)

  * The Operating System platform that you may be running (e.g. Macintosh® or Windows®)

  * Search Words or Terms that are passed from a Search Engine (e.g. Google® or Yahoo!®)

  * Information readily available and stored in your Adobe® Flash ‘System.Capabilities' Object.

There is absolutely nothing special about the information just described, and the practice of collecting this data has been generally standardized by virtually every Web Server on the Internet today.

The purpose for this information is actually two-fold. One, ecobee inc. has found it advantageous to examine visitor traffic in its aggregate, so that we can ensure maximum compatibility for the various Browsers and Operating Systems that visit our site. Additionally, as any business should attest, it is our desire to generate greater amounts of visitor traffic. By analyzing visitation patterns, referring URLs and Search Engine terms, we can strategically enhance our exposure on the Internet.

### What about Cookies?

Cookies are small pieces of data that are transferred to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser from our Web Server. A cookie cannot read data from your hard disk or read cookie files that may have been created from other sites. The ecobee inc. website utilizes cookies only as a means of providing personalization features to our visitors. For example, we utilize cookies to manage your login to your personalized web portal once you have registered your ecobee Thermostat.

You can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of your browser. Typically, by accessing the browser's help feature you can obtain information on how to prevent your browser from accepting all cookies or to notify you when a cookie is being sent. If you choose not to accept these cookies, your experience at our website and other websites may be diminished and some features may not work as intended.

### What information does ecobee inc. collect when I purchase something?

If you purchase something, such as an ecobee Thermostat or thermostat accessory direct from ecobee inc., we need to obtain the appropriate information in order to complete the purchase transaction. Depending upon the method of payment that you select and your location, the required information may vary. However, generally speaking we will need:

  * YourName

  * Billing Address (for Credit Card Orders)

  * Shipping Address

  * E-Mail Address

  * Phone Number

  * Credit Card Number (for Credit Card Orders)

  * Expiration Date (for Credit Card Orders)

  * CCV2 Code (for Credit Card Orders)

We use shopping cart features that safeguard this information by using industry standard SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encrypted servers. SSL encodes the information transferred between you and the server, rendering it unreadable to anyone trying to intercept the information.

If you buy an ecobee Thermostat and register your thermostat, you will be able to remotely view and control your thermostat from anywhere on the internet via a mobile application or our web portal. To enable these remote functions, your thermostat needs to transmit temperature and HVAC operational data to the web portal. These transmissions are fully encrypted. The temperature and HVAC operational data will be stored by the web portal to provide you with historical reports. In addition, we will ask you for information about your house (for example, your address so that we can determine the nearest local weather station) and we will keep information about how your house performs (for example how quickly it heats up or cools down) and how your heating and cooling system performs. We use this data to make more intelligent decisions about how to manage your heating and cooling.

We may also anonymously aggregate your data with data from other homes in order to create reports, benchmarks and allow you (and others) to compare energy usage, on an anonymous basis, with similar homes.

ecobee may also send you information regarding your Thermostat's operations, software updates or promotions via the “What's New” widget on the web portal. We will also request your e-mail address – this allows us to email you alerts and reminders and allows someone to contact you if you so request.

If you register for one of our mailing lists, we will use your email address to send you updates on the mailing list topic such as announcements, news and new products or services. You have the option of ‘Unsubscribing' from out Mailing List at any time, thereby disabling any further such e-mail communication from being sent to you. If you wish to have specific communications with a member of the ecobee inc. staff, you will be required to provide specific information that will be routed to the appropriate contact within ecobee inc.We maintain a strict ‘No Spam or UCE' policy that means we do not intend to sell, rent, or otherwise give your e-mail address to a third-party, without your consent.

If you agree to participate in a utility-sponsored electricity usage program, information relating to electricity use may be forwarded to your utility provider in order to make intelligent decisions relating to electricity production and conservation. ecobee inc. or your utility provider may also anonymously aggregate your data with data from other homes in order to create reports, benchmarks and allow you (and others) to compare energy usage, on an anonymous basis, with similar homes. You may also receive messages on your thermostat, via the “What's New” widget from your utility provider. Your utility provider will not sell, rent, or otherwise give your e-mail address to a third-party, without your consent.

The contractor that installs your thermostat may link their business contact information with your thermostat. This information, if inputted, will appear with the Alerts and Reminders that are generated by the thermostat and can be found in the Settings-> About function on the thermostat or in the Settings-> About widget in your personalized web portal. From time to time, the contractor may send maintenance reminders and/or promotional offers that will appear on the “What's New” widget. This contractor-provided information will not appear directly on the thermostat screen or be sent to you by e-mail. The contractor will use this web portal information to service their accounts and will agree to a strict ‘No Spam, or UCE' as defined above.

ecobee inc. provides technicians who install the ecobee Thermostat with a contractor web portal. This contractor web portal allows the technicians to track and maintain the thermostats that they have installed and may contain the following information: Thermostat ID number, the status of the thermostat (online/offline), the customer's name, address, phone number and/or email. The technician may also be able to view service notes relating to previous service calls, and the time of the next scheduled service call or service reminder. If your ecobee thermostat is a communicating thermostat, it may also forward operational and diagnostics information from compatible HVAC equipment (furnace, air conditioner, etc.) to the contractor web portal, if the communicating functionality is enabled. You can remove yourself from your technicians list of thermostats by using the Settings->About widget in your personalized web portal. If you have rated your contractor using the web portal application, the contractor may be able to see their average rating (i.e., the average of all ratings for that contractor) as well as anonymous comments from users.

### Will ecobee Inc. disclose the information collected to Third Parties?

ecobee Inc. will only disclose your personal information or any of its log file information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such actions are necessary to:

  * Conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on ecobee Inc..

  * Protect and defend the rights or property of ecobee Inc., or visitors of ecobee Inc..

  * Identify persons who may be violating the law, the legal notice, or the rights of third parties.

  * Cooperate with the investigations of purported unlawful activities.

ecobee inc.uses reasonable precautions to keep the information disclosed to us secure. ecobee inc.reserves the right to transfer information in connection with the sale of all or part of ecobee inc.capital stock or assets to any third party. Furthermore, we are not responsible for any breach of security or for any actions of any third parties that receive the information. ecobee inc.also provides ‘links' to a wide variety of other web sites on the Internet. We are not responsible for their Privacy Policies or how those web sites manage information about their users. We strongly urge you to check with those web sites to determine their privacy policy.

Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be posted on this page so that you are always aware of the information that we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

Please send any notices or requests regarding this Privacy Policy by care of e-mail to: [legal@ecobee.com](mailto:legal@ecobee.com)

### Your California privacy rights

California residents can now ask companies with whom they have an established business relationship to provide certain information about the companies' sharing of personal information with third parties for direct marketing purposes during the past year.

ecobee does not share personal information about its customers with third parties for their own marketing purposes.

To request a printed copy of this disclosure from ecobee pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, please contact us via email at [info@ecobee.com](mailto:info@ecobee.com) or write to us at:

ecobee inc.   
Attn: California privacy rights   
333 Adelaide St W, 6th Floor   
Toronto, ON M5V 1R5, Canada 

Copyright © 2008, 2011 ecobee inc. All Rights Reserved. ecobee inc. and any marks and logos are Registered Trademarks of ecobee inc.. All other trademarks listed are the property of their respective owners.   
Revision: September 2011 

  * "I have 9 ecobee thermostats across 3 properties and love your product." - Roger, Commercial Customer

  * "What a great product! it performs as is stated. nothing better than turning on the ac from my iphone and coming home to a cool house!" - T.Y.

  * "You guys are one of a kind - that's a good thing! Thanks for taking the time to answer my questions. I'm very excited to start using this smart device." - R.T.

  * "I love my ecobee thermostats - I have two and in the first year of having them I saved enough money on my oil bill to pay for my thermostat." - A.G.

  * "Abilene Texas has an entire new housing development using ecobee - You should come here and see how your units keep up with the Texas summer heat!" - G.W.P.

  * "My favorite thing? Warming up the master bedroom from my iPhone when heading home in the evening on a cold winter day. And vice versa..." - L.S.R.

  * "The ecobee thermostat and iPhone app was worth every penny. My wife tells me on every trip to the vacation home what a great purchase it was." - R.B., Homeowner

  * "The online web portal is revolutionary and is just as simple to navigate as the thermostat itself." - Joe, Contractor
